the one of the things that we're
realizing is that when teachers have the
opportunity to experience stem
themselves the problem-solving the
cooperative learning that they're not
having a teacher tell them the answer
and they see the success that the
students have there's no going back
we've all been in those professional
development sessions where the presenter
says all right we know how important
instructional strategies are and
engagement and then they sit there for
two hours and read a PowerPoint to us
that's not our professional elements at
all the atmosphere is just different
it's not like teaching in a school year
like I have so much fun doing this even
though I'm a teacher my students at
school we have so much requirements I
don't get that time to see them excel
fully and they're creative and
problem-solving ideas we're here it's
completely fund based we're really
trying to emulate that in our
professional development and allow
teachers to do what we're expecting the
students my biggest takeaway from the
experience overall is the ability to
connect with other teachers and really
being able to engross myself over the
summer in a summer long learning process
rather than a one-day professional
development I think one of the things
that we do best is we have the ability
to customize our professional
development to meet the needs of the
school because we don't want to be that
one little thing that you know seemed
great but nothing actually ends up with
it